The Invoke Functions enable you to schedule
Invoke は一定のディレイ（遅延）後に
a function call after some specified time delay.
関数呼び出しをスケジュールする関数です
This allows us to build a useful method
この関数を利用することでタイミングが
call system that is time sensitive.
重要なシステムを便利に構築することができます
Here we have a scene in Unity with an empty game object.
いま表示されているのは空っぽのゲームオブジェクトが配置された Unity のシーンです
The game object has an InvokeScript attached to it.
このゲームオブジェクトには InvokeScript がアタッチされています
In the InvokeScript we have
この InvokeScript には
a public game object named Target.
public なゲームオブジェクト target があります
We also have a method named SpawnObject.
またこの他にも SpawnObject というメソッドもあります
The SpawnObject method simply instantiates the
SpawnObject メソッドは単純に target オブジェクトを
target object at the position (0, 2, 0).
位置 (0, 2, 0) でインスタンス化しています
In the start method we call the function Invoke.
そして Start メソッドで Invoke 関数を呼び出しています
The invoke function takes 2 parameters.
Invoke 関数は 2 つのパラメーターを取ります
A sting containing the name of the method we want to call
呼び出したいメソッド名の文字列と
and an amount of time to delay in seconds.
ディレイとして指定したい秒数です
We can see from this line of code that after 2 seconds
つまりこの行では 2 秒後に SpawnObject メソッドが
the SpawnObject method will be called.
呼び出されるように指定されているわけです
It is worth noting that only methods which
なお Invoke を使って呼び出せるのは
take no parameters and have a return
パラメーターを取らず戻り値の型がない（void）
type of Void can be called using invoke.
メソッドのみです
Back in Unity let's run our scene.
さて Unity に戻りシーンを実行してみましょう
We can see that after 2 seconds an orb
実行してみると 2 秒後にオーブが
is instantiated and falls to the ground.
インスタンス化されて地面に落ちるのが確認できます
This is useful for calling methods a single time.
確かにこれは一度メソッドを呼び出すには便利そうですが
But what if we wanted to call a method repeatedly?
同じメソッドを何度も呼び出すときはどうしたらいいでしょう?
This can be easily done using the
そういった場合は 単純に
InvokeRepeating function.
InvokeRepeating 関数を使います
Here in our scene we have the same
このシーンでは同じ 空っぽの
empty game object.
ゲームオブジェクトがあります
This time however there is an
ただし今回アタッチされているスクリプトは
InvokeRepeatingScript attached to it.
InvokeRepeatingScript です
In the InvokeRepeatingScript
InvokeRepeatingScript の中は
we can see that things are laid out almost exactly
基本的に InvokeScript とほぼ同じ構造で
the same as in the InvokeScript.
作られているのが見えるでしょうか
We still have a public game object named Target
引き続き target という名前の public なゲームオブジェクトがあり
and we still have a SpawnObject method.
SpawnObject メソッドもあります
The SpawnObject method in this script
そしてこのスクリプトの SpawnObject メソッドも
still instantiates the target object
target オブジェクトをインスタンス化していますが
but now it does so at a random X and Z position.
今回は X と Z の座標がランダムになっています
In the start method we have a call to
さてこのスクリプトの Start メソッドは
the InvokeRepeating function.
InvokeRepeating 関数を呼び出しています
This function takes 3 arguments.
この関数は 3 つの引数を取ります
A string containing the name of the method
最初は呼び出したい
that we wish to call.
メソッド名の文字列
The delay in seconds before it calls the method
次に  メソッドを呼び出すまで待機する秒数
and a delay in seconds between each
最後にメソッドを繰り返し呼び出す際の
subsequent call of the method.
間隔となる秒数です
We can see from this line of code the
つまりこの行では 2 秒後に SpawnObject メソッドが
SpawnObject will be called after 2 seconds
呼び出され  その後は
and then be called again every 1 second.
1 秒ごとに繰り返し 呼び出されます
Let's see this in action.
では実際に見てみましょう
In Unity we can run our scene.
このシーンは Unity 上でそのまま実行できます
We will see that after 2 seconds an orb gets instantiated.
実行するとまず 2 秒後にオーブがインスタンス化され
Then every 1 second
その後は 1 秒ごとに
another orb is created.
新たなオーブが作成されていきます
This will keep going infinitely and fill
オーブは無限に生成されていくので
our entire scene with orbs.
やがてシーンがオーブで埋め尽くされます
Obviously it is important to know
というわけで InvokeRepeating で呼び出した
how to stop a method we have called
メソッドをどのように止めるかを
with the InvokeRepeating function.
理解しておくことは重要です
In order to stop, all instances of
このスクリプトによる Invoke コールの
an invoked call from this script
全インスタンスを止めるには
we can use the CancelInvoke method.
CancelInvoke メソッドを使います
If we wish to only stop a specific Invoke
なお特定の Invoke だけを止めたい場合は
we can parse in a string containing the name of
止めたいメソッドの名前を含む文字列を
the method we wish to stop.
パースすることもできます